# **Jess Dowd**

Full Stack Web Developer | Software Developer

LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio | jessalyndowd@gmail.com | +66 62-398-6762 | MO, USA (Remote)

## **Summary**

Multilingual full stack developer with 1+ year of experience in web development. Seeking a full-time position available to start immediately to use proven React skills to meet business needs. Through my past experiences, I can balance the need of users and businesses to understand how I can contribute as a full-stack web developer and help them solve their problems.

## Technical Skills | Languages

JavaScript, JavaScript Frameworks, React, Node.js, Algorithms, Continuous Integration (CI), Data Structures, Deployment, OOP, Unit Testing, Babel, Figma, jQuery, Git/GitHub, JSON, SQL, CSS Frameworks, Styled-Components, SCSS, MySQL, HTML | English (Native), Thai (Basic, A2), Mandarin (Beginner, A1)

## **Technical Projects**

## Real world Project - 07/2021 Website | Demo | Code links

Front-end Application using API to fetch data and vanilla JavaScript to add interactivity

- built maintainable, reusable UI components using API and JS
- Built reactive design using CSS Flexbox from Figma specifications
- Successfully implemented webpack and Babel to increase load speed

### Final Project - 09/2021 Website | Demo | Code links

Front-end Application using API to fetch data and vanilla JavaScript to add interactivity

- built maintainable, reusable UI components using API and JS
- Built reactive design using CSS Flexbox from Figma specifications
- Successfully implemented webpack and Babel to increase load speed

### **Experience**

#### Freelance | Web Developer | 04/2021 - Current

- Designed and built sites using technologies such as NextJs and ReactJS.
- Performed SEO analysis of companies to better rank on Google analytics.
- Researched and improved overall site interaction and design.

### Ecommerce WordPress | Sales Manager - Jessential | 2013 - 2017

- Managing sales on platforms such as WordPress, Amazon, and eBay
- Providing on-the-job training for employees and task delegation.

#### **Education**

#### Practicum by Yandex | Web Engineering Program | 2020-2021

 Completed 15 independent projects using languages HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, JS frameworks, libraries like React, and industry best practice standards for clean code.

### Bachelor in Business Administration (B.B.A) | Burapha University | 2020-2024

Elected Major Leader of Finance for the class of 2020 - GPA 3.75